If the Minister can really cause miracles with his Philosopher's Stone,
then why did it turn out like this?
Please cease fighting!
Send out the Minister!
Give us the Minister!
Rose, is it okay that
we're not fighting?
Against whom?
How foolish.
Humans are foolish beyond saving.
Foolish! Foolish!
With things going this well,
such foolishness is refreshing.
Well, well, if it isn't
the almighty Minister.
Almighty!
All I did was incite the
members of the order,
and the believers
began killing each other.
And the military is just adding fuel to
the fire by trying to quell the disorder.
No matter how many times they repeat themselves,
they never know enough to learn.
Humans are foolish,
miserable creatures.
All of this to create
a Philosopher's Stone.
And now, I can finally...
return to this adorable form.
That again?
You enjoy making yourself up as young, huh?
What else can I do?
I've forgotten
what I originally looked like, after all.
Wh-What's going on here?
The Minister...
What have you done with the real Minister?!
What do we do?
Why don't we just tell him the truth? The Minister has long since—
Can I eat him?
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Come to mention it,
I got some information saying
that guy is headed from Central to East.
You mean the State Alchemist killer?
The Flame Colonel is in East City, along with...
By now, the Fullmetal pipsqueak is making his stay there.
Really...
Right now,
that boy is the closest one
to our goal.
We can't have that guy
just going around on his own.
Lust, that was delicious!
Wipe your mouth, Gluttony.
Right, right...
So, what was this guy named?
"Scar"?
The scarred man?
We don't know his
real identity, after all.
We've got eyewitness testimony saying he has a large scar on his forehead,
so that's what we call him.
And he's the one who killed a number of State Alchemists in Central?
Nine of them.
Four just in Central.
If you count the whole country,
nine State Alchemists
have fallen by his hand.
If you include other
personnel around them,
it's well into the dozens.
Judging from the wounds, it looks like
they blew up from the inside.
As far as his weapons and his objectives go,
we don't know a thing.
And so, the folks at the Central Command Center panicked.
They made the excuse that
they were escorting the Führer
and went on this trip en masse, then?
So the killer won't come to this backwoods place, huh?
You're here, and all.
Those who demoted you
three years ago are aware...
of your abilities.
Now I'm beginning to
want to run away too.
The issue is who
his next target will be.
Pardon me...
Oh, sorry, but I have a cute little daughter who's about to turn three—
Telephone for you.
Oh, thanks.
Yes, hello, this is Hughes.
Major?
Understood.
The body of one of the soldiers patrolling East City Station has been found.
Blown up from the inside?
Doctor Marcoh?
You mean Mauro-sensei?
No, Marcoh.
But there's only one doctor in this village,
and that's Mauro-sensei.
As you can see, the folks along this road are poor,
and we had to take half a day
just to get to East City to see a doctor.
He's a nice fellow.
He'll make sure to see even patients who were given up on as incurable elsewhere.
When I got my leg caught under a tractor and it looked like I was going to die,
he fixed me up just right.
When he was treating him, right? There was this flash of light!
Right, right!
Light...
That's alchemy all right.
It's Doctor Marcoh.
But he's on the run
from the military, right?
Why would he become a doctor? There'd be stories about him.
This is awful!
I'm getting straw inside me!
Who is that?
He's a State Alchemist—
one of those who was with the Führer when they came from Central.
But why is he here?
Did he follow us?
The Colonel said he never reported Marcoh's whereabouts to Central.
Let's hurry!
Marcoh's house should be close by.
H-Hold on! We just wanted...
A State Alchemist, you say?!
Have you come to take me back?!
Er, you're the Crystal Alchemist, Doctor Marcoh-san, right?
I don't want to go back there!
Please! I couldn't stand that!
It's not like that! Hear us out!
Look, that's dangerous!
Or have you come to silence me?!
You think you can kill me? I... I...
Al...
It's all right.
Even if you kill me, I won't die.
You're...
I see, you're the Fullmetal Alchemist...
No, that would be me!
I'm him, actually.
I deserted the battlefield,
and when I did, I stole the research materials that I had at the time.
The military is probably
still after those materials.
That's it!
The truth is, we're looking into human transmutation—
I can't...
show you anything.
Orders from above notwithstanding,
I stained my hands with that research.
And then, it was used in the
massacre of the Eastern Rebellion.
Massacre?
You mean the uprising at Ishbal?
It was terrible.
It was a truly terrible battle.
Children... women...
They were all killed.
There was no justifiable reason for it.
It was reason enough that they were the people of Ishbal and defied the military.
I could never fully make up for what
I did there even if I gave up my own life.
Even so, I decided to do all that I can, which is why I am a doctor here.
Go back.
I'm a State Alchemist!
I have a right to see your research!
As little as you are?
I'll bet you were blinded by
the abundant research funding
and numerous privileges,
so you got yourself certified.
What foolishness.
If you were there during
the rebellion, you would also—
I know!
I know what we're doing is stupid.
But even so...
Marcoh-san...
About five years ago, you treated
the babies at Xenotime, didn't you?
The babies from that time are now doing fine.
Brother!
No transmutation circle?!
Is this the red water of Xenotime?
No, this appears to be much clearer.
Stop!
Brother!
Brother, this is wrong!
Let go of me!
Brother!
Let go of me, I said!
It's not a liquid?
Brother, it...
It looks like that thing that the Minister at Liore had.
The Sage's Stone, the Celestial Stone...
the Great Elixir, the Red Tincture, the Fifth Element...
Just as it is called by many names,
its form is also not limited to that of a stone.
Brigadier General Grand...
Brigadier General?
My, you've moved up in the world.
Crystal Alchemist,
you will turn over the Philosopher's Stone, along with all of your materials.
Philosopher's Stone?! That?!
At best, it is an experimentally produced item.
There's no telling when it will
reach its limit and become unusable.
It's an unstable, defective product,
and it's different from the genuine article.
But during the rebellion,
it did augment our abilities,
and we displayed tremendous power!
So, are you saying
that in the past,
the military researched
the Philosopher's Stone?
Never mind that it isn't perfect.
If that was made by human hands...
it means that it's possible to
create a Philosopher's Stone as well!
Where is the manufacturing technique?!
What do you mean to do
once you see it, Fullmetal Alchemist?
The research is top secret
and falls under my jurisdiction.
I cannot permit you
to see the materials.
Let's go!
L-Let go of me!
No! No!
Please don't! Forgive me!
I don't want to go back there!
I don't want to go back!
I've had enough of it!
Please forgive me!
I can't stand it!
I can't stand anymore!
It's just like that other time...
Brother!
I may not have grown at all,
but I can't let my heart stay stunted!
Who's that?
Iron Blood Alchemist, Basque Grand...
Too bad for you!
I now have this!
Stop!
That's...
That's the guy I saw three years ago
in Central. I'm sure of it...
Never mind that! This is bad!
My instincts are telling me to run,
but my legs won't move!
Crystal Alchemist, Doctor Marcoh...
I heard that you were dead.
I must take special care...
to kill you!
You're...
I see. This must be fate.
In the name of God,
thou shalt perish!
Edward-kun!
What are you giving up for?!
Run!
Fullmetal Alchemist!
You will not escape either!
He knows me?
What's going on here?
I've done plenty of stuff
to get people mad at me,
but I've never given anyone
a reason to come after my life!
Brother, this way!
Who are you?!
Why are you after us?!
If you are creators, then there must also be a destroyer.
Edward-kun, leave me behind and run!
You have a fine look in your eyes.
My older brother also had the same look in his eyes.
Eyes that were strong, that peered far away
into the endless distance...
Three years ago, was it?
I was glad to hear that you had
given up being a State Alchemist.
That's too bad.
However!
Too slow!
Brother!
Al!
Make no mistake.
I meant to destroy a human body,
so you got away with just that crack.
Stay out of this.
My only enemy is the State Alchemist.
Why?
Why are you after us?
Alchemists are those who take things
from their natural form
and transform them into something grotesque.
That is to say, they profane God, the creator of all things.
As an agent of God,
I am he who hands down his judgment.
I'm an alchemist too!
I may not have the state's certification...
Why do you wish to die?
You mentioned your older brother a moment ago, right?
Then you should understand!
There's no way anyone could watch their brother get killed.
Even you—
I do understand!
The way I felt when I had to watch as
my brother was killed before my eyes...
That is exactly...
why I must now...!
I told you, you're too slow.
Automail?
So your right arm brings forth
nothing but destruction as well?
Don't go lumping my
right arm in with yours!
A State Alchemist?
Are you here to take Marcoh-san?!
I'm sorry I'm late.
I was assigned by the Lt.
Colonel to guard you.
By Lt. Colonel Hughes?
Agent of God, you say?
In that case, try passing judgment upon me.
For I am the Strong Arm Alchemist,
Alex Louis Armstrong!
What a fine day this is!
That you would come forward
and save me the trouble of finding you...
Could this be the grace of God?
Allow me to show you
the artistic alchemy
that has been passed down among
the Armstrong family for generations!
Another shot!
As you can see,
there are only children here!
There aren't any of the guerillas you're looking for!
Does this mean you've abandoned
the so-called teachings of Cornello?
Fine.
Tell us the location of the faction that's resisting military rule!
No!
We came to liberate this town from Cornello!
Don't you understand?!
This town is our home.
We're going to move forward,
even if it's only a little at a time, under our own power.
Our legs are fine, after all!
You dropped this.
You didn't think about
running away with this?
You used it to treat people in that clinic, right?
I can't forget the looks on the faces of
those people who told us about you today.
That belongs to those people, and so do you.
Can you walk?
Okay, let's go.
Someplace where neither that guy nor the military will follow us.
Can we escape them?
You still have your legs, don't you?
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 15: "The Ishbal Massacre"
We don't know anything.
But you can't use ignorance as an excuse to absolve yourself.